1x.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy • 1x.com

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from 1x.com (the "Site").

## 

DEVICE INFORMATION  
When you visit the Site, we may automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as "Device Information".  
We collect Device Information using the following technologies:  
\- "Cookies" are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).  
\- "Log files" track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.  
\- "Web beacons", "tags", and "pixels" are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.  
SHOPPING INFORMATION  
When you submit information (including text, images, videos, and other information) to us or add products to your shopping cart or save products to your favorites page or make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we may collect certain information from you, including your name, company name, email address (or other contact details), shopping cart items, favorite list items, order history, billing address, shipping address, shipping method, and payment information (including credit/debit card numbers, PayPal details, and details of other payment methods). We refer to this information as "Shopping Information". We collect Shopping Information in our "session/order database".  
MEMBER INFORMATION  
When you sign up for a membership at the Site or use our member services that are available to registered members (for example, our photo community, curation, critique, tutorials, forum, contests, and blog) or make your photos available for sales at the Site, we may collect certain information from you, including your name, email address (or other contact details), country of residence, date of birth, profile image, cover image, your biography, the photos you upload on the Site, public comments on photos or in our forum or in photo critique or in guestbooks or in our blog or in endorsements, private messages sent to other members through our internal messaging system, curation comments about photos, who you are following and who is following you, photos added to favorites and/or lists and/or albums, votes on photos in curation, blog articles if you are featured in our blog, photo tutorials, groups you have joined, scores you have earned for activity on the Site, your title if you are part of a team, PayPal email address, time when features and print rights where enabled and disabled, photos for sale, photos sold, royalty earned and if and when earnings have been paid out, and the print partners your photos have been distributed to. We refer to this information as "Member Information". We collect Member Information in our "session/order database".  
When we talk about "Personal Information" in this Privacy Policy, we are talking collectively about Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. 

## 

For the purposes of improving and optimizing our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with our Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns), we may process Device Information. Our legitimate interest is to analyze and improve our Site, services, and products.  
For the purposes of administering your purchase, supplying the purchased products or services, and keeping proper records of those transactions, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. The processing is necessary for the performance of our contract with you and our legitimate interest is to properly administer our Site and our business.  
For the purposes of saving your shopping cart and reminding you of the abandoned products therein, we may process Device Information and Shopping Information. Our legitimate interest is to make your purchase as easy as possible for the products you have expressed interest in by adding them to your shopping cart.  
For the purposes of communicating with you about the Site and/or the products or services that you have purchased, managing our relationship with you, and keeping records of those communications, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. The processing is necessary for the performance of our contract with you and our legitimate interest is to provide you with convenient customer service, properly manage our customer relationships, and properly administer our Site and our business.  
For the purpose of screening for potential risk or fraud, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. Our legitimate interest is your security, the security of others and our Site, and to properly administer our Site and our business.  
For the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. Our legitimate interest is the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights, and the legal rights of others.  
For compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. The processing is necessary for us to comply with applicable legislation and our legitimate interest is the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights, and the legal rights of others.  
For the purpose of sending you relevant notifications or newsletters, we may process Device Information, Shopping Information, and Member Information. This processing is based on your consent when you subscribed to our newsletter or based on our legitimate interest to send relevant marketing communications to you after you have made a purchase or signed up for a membership at the Site. You can unsubscribe anytime using the opt-out link in the email.  
For the purpose of providing you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications about our products and services, we may process Device Information and Shopping Information. Our legitimate interest is to provide you with relevant advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you.  
For the purpose of publishing a review that you have written about the Site, we may process information about the name and information that you provided in your review. Our legitimate interest is to inform people about what our customers experienced doing business with us.  
For the purposes of providing our member services, enabling the publication of members' photos and/or other information that members post for publication on the Site, and enabling and managing the sales of members' photos, we may process Member Information. The processing is necessary for the performance of our contracts with our registered members and our legitimate interest is to properly administer our Site and our business.  
Please do not supply any other person's Personal Information to us, unless we prompt you to do so. 

## 

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use Personal Information, as described above. To process your payments, we share Personal Information with our payment providers. To deliver your products and manage returns, we share Personal Information with our fulfillment and shipping providers. To provide you with convenient customer service, we share Personal Information with our communication tool providers. To make our marketing communications more relevant, we share Personal Information with marketing platforms such as Google and Facebook. To enable and manage the sales of members' photos, we share Member Information with print partners. We also use Google Analytics and Hotjar to help us understand how our customers use the Site. For more information about how Google and Hotjar use your Personal Information, read [Google's Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Hotjar's Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy). You can also [opt out of Google Analytics here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) and [opt out of Hotjar here](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).  
Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights. 

## 

Please note that we do not alter our Site's data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser. 

## 

If you are a European resident, you have the rights to access Personal Information we hold about you and to ask that your Personal Information be corrected, updated, deleted, or restricted. You also have the rights to object, complain, withdraw consent, and to data portability. Read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights. If you would like to exercise these rights, please contact us through the contact information below.  
Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe, including to the United States. 

## 

Personal Information for any purposes will not be kept for longer than is necessary for those purposes. We may maintain Device Information for a maximum period of 3 years and Shopping Information and Member Information for a maximum period of 10 years unless and until you ask us to delete this information, or as long as required by accounting laws, money laundry legislations, or other legal obligations to which we are subject. 

## 

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons. 

## 

The Site is not intended for individuals under the age of 18. 

## 

For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by email at support@1x.com or by mail at 1x Innovations AB, Attn: Privacy Support, Regeringsgatan 65, 3rd Floor, SE-11156 Stockholm, Sweden.

 _Updated: January 7, 2019_

## Need Help? 

Our customer support will be happy to assist you.

## Join Our Insider List

Enter your email

By joining you agree to our terms and privacy
